<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-01-12T06:21:03-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Justin Ho</title><subtitle>Build Jekyll site with the GitBook style.
</subtitle><author><name>HE Tao</name></author><entry><title type="html">_</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/2023-12-31-_.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="_" /><published>2023-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-12-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/_</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/2023-12-31-_.html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="not-today">Not Today</h3>

<p><em>8th of January 2024</em></p>

<p>Mondays are said to be the worst, and they are. As I am drinking my wine, drowning my woes; I could not help to feel a little part of me wants me to feel worse than I actually am, manufacturing dissent, if you will, in this life that I have. That could be entirely true. But what gripe do I have in evaluating decent work done by brilliant participants?</p>

<p>Could one tell? Could one tell that I am being immature, complaining in the sidelines while allowing this to live in my head rent free? Why do I actually care, or why do I not? I should make a decision. And the truth is, there is a lot of wisdom in my professors who could navigate all this bullshit and stay afloat regardless, and maybe I am here to learn that. Tolerance to this, whole, farce… At least that is how it feels at times.</p>

<p>Learning to be grateful is indeed hard, especially when you are raised so privileged. If you could not name the problem, then, it isn’t a problem. It is probably in your head.</p>

<h3 id="a-personal-reminder">A Personal Reminder</h3>

<p><em>31st of December 2023</em></p>

<p>It would be disingenuous to say that I had to leave behind a lot in 2023. I did, but they were choices. Intentional, brimmed with the excitement of change. I had given up many things, and in return, I had received a lot. That, I should always remind myself.</p>

<p>As the arbitrary number approaches that defines our world, I have the all too familiar task to do in my small apartment in Boston, MA. A state whose name I could not spell without doing a Google Search. aAstate that I grew to adore and love, but harbour a sense of distaste from the lingering memories of comfort from Lincoln.</p>

<p><em>‘Estas por encima del mundo’</em> is perhaps not the right way to phrase things, neither does it make me feel better about myself. But I am somewhere that matters, somewhere that, that if I just could be honest to myself, is miles better than what most people have. That, I do have to remind myself that.</p>]]></content><author><name>Justin Ho</name></author><category term="Jekyll" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Not Today]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Book Journal</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/2023-12-24-books.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Book Journal" /><published>2023-12-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-12-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/books</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/2023-12-24-books.html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="same-as-ever">Same As Ever</h3>

<p><em>Listened, December 2023</em></p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1680687321i/125116554.jpg" width="150" /></div>

<p><br /></p>

<p>If you’d told me that I’d be reading a <em>‘futurist’</em> book called <em>Same As Ever</em>, I’d probably call you out for your bullshit. Yet it was, oddly entertaining, not too sure about the validity, but quipped with an unforgetable line <em>“The grass is always greener on the side that is fertilized with bullshit.”</em></p>

<p>With my attention honing into my current disdain of “predictions”, or what not, this book does resonate, and does highlight something most statisticians would agree. That is, we can only reliably interpolate our results to the future and have more confidence in it for things that don’t change, not those that do. Perhaps those are the things worth investigating, a food for thought.</p>

<h3 id="dirtbag-massachusetts">Dirtbag, Massachusetts</h3>

<p><em>December 2023</em></p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1651649028i/54860230.jpg" width="150" /></div>

<p><br /></p>

<p>Fitzgerald had the life that I will never have, and I am not saying it enviously in any way. My life, up to this point, has been immeasurably better by any accounts, and maybe this is some kind of poverty porn for me. The very raw and honest stories by Fitzgerald gave me a different perspective of how life could have been, but in many ways, how I have chosen to see my life thus far. I was never as carefree as he was in his early twenties, and that is a good thing, right? Not sure if I can unlearn that.</p>

<p>But troubles and traumas give you learnable lessons too, and I believe (in fact quite explicitly stated by Fitzgerald) that he wanted to impart some of the bitter lessons he learned. And that is his life, for better or worse. It reminded me of a Chinese saying “出淤泥而不染” that I wish is true, but is unfortunately not in most cases. And some traumas linger, just as his tattoos on him. Not sure if I can unlearn that.</p>

<h3 id="on-earth-were-briefly-gorgeous">On Earth We’re Briefly Gorgeous</h3>

<p><em>Read first in the midst of the pandemic, then again in November 2023</em></p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1615580168i/41880609.jpg" width="150" /></div>

<p><br /></p>

<p><em>“I am thinking of beauty again, how some things are hunted because we have deemed them beautiful. If, relative to the history of our planet, an individual life is so short, a blink, as they say, then to be gorgeous, even from the day you’re born to the day you die, is to be gorgeous only briefly.”</em> ― <strong>Ocean Vuong</strong></p>

<p>I picked this book up in all sincerity because I was longing for some gay fiction, with hope that a little smut will sneak in, and boy did I get some of that. What I’ve not expected from this experience, was a heart-wrenching story that made me think, and cry, and it enveloped me with emotions I’ve never felt with this masterpiece. My eyes scanned through the words, to only go a few sentences back, adjusting myself to sit upright, and carefully read the lines, looking around, zoning out, reminding myself this is not real life. Loving someone can be so painful, when we are on divergent paths. Losing them forever, is a stab in the heart.</p>

<p><em>I miss you more than I remember you.</em> ― <strong>Ocean Vuong</strong></p>

<h3 id="america-is-not-the-heart">America is Not the Heart</h3>

<p><em>Read in November 2023</em></p>

<div style="text-align: center"><img src="https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/S/compressed.photo.goodreads.com/books/1501492676i/34939312.jpg" width="150" /></div>

<p><br /></p>

<p><em>“You already know that the first thing that makes you foreign to a place is to be born poor in it; you don’t need to emigrate to America to feel what you already felt when you were ten, looking up at the rickety concrete roof above your head and knowing that one more bad typhoon would bring it down to crush your bones and the bones of all your siblings sleeping next to you; or selling fruit by the side of the road to people who made sure to never really look at you, made sure not to touch your hands when they put the money in it. You’ve been foreign all your life. When you finally leave, all you’re hoping for is a more bearable kind of foreignness.”</em> ― <strong>Elaine Castillo</strong></p>

<p>My home to me, today at least, is as foreign as it can get. Here, without my family nor loved ones, but despite the distance, feels more like ‘home’. A story about leaving behind the world you knew, one that spat on your face, and turning around to another that you don’t belong, but finding warmth and familiarty in it. I’d like to tell that story. And of course, mine wasn’t fraught with violence, abandonment, and unrelentless work, but the book resonated with me in inexplicable ways. It reminded me of mum. It reminded me of the journey, of immigration, the idealization of home, to find disappointing apparitions of the past that haunt you till this day. Regardless, Castillo chose to close the story with pancit, a lot of it in fact, filling the mouths (and hearts) of the De Vera family in spite of the simmering tensions that characterize family life.</p>]]></content><author><name>Justin Ho</name></author><category term="Jekyll" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Same As Ever]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Notes</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/2023-12-24-notes.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Notes" /><published>2023-12-24T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-12-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/notes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/2023-12-24-notes.html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="bayesian-data-analysis">Bayesian Data Analysis</h3>

<p>This is my ongoing work with Jonathan Min to go through the lectures as well as exercises by following the lecture series taught by Prof. Aki Vehtari on Bayesian Data Analysis, and the book with the same name by Prof. Vehtari and his coauthors.</p>

<div style="text-align: center">
<a href="https://www.overleaf.com/read/xsvznyjgqdgx#8fe54c" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">
<button class="button-23"> <i class="fa fa-leaf"></i> Overleaf
</button> 
</a>
</div>

<h1 id="discontinued-notes">Discontinued Notes</h1>

<h3 id="machine-learning-with-graphs">Machine Learning with Graphs</h3>

<p>I wrote this during the pandemic, and this is based on Stanford’s lectures on ML with graphs. It was really interesting, and I learned this because I thought I needed to know methods from this for my paper, but… it was just more on personal learning (which I don’t regret).</p>

<div style="text-align: center">
<a href="https://github.com/justinhjy1004/justinhjy1004.github.io/blob/master/assets/Machine_Learning_with_Graphs_Notes.pdf?raw=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">
<button class="button-23"> <i class="fa fa-file-pdf-o"></i>  PDF
</button> 
</a>
</div>]]></content><author><name>Justin Ho</name></author><category term="Jekyll" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bayesian Data Analysis]]></summary></entry></feed>